Amos Moyo



Personal Details

Name Amos Moyo Date of Birth 24-06-1996

Address Nairobi, 43844-00100, Kenya

Mobile +254710510906

Email amosmoyo5300@gmail.com

LinkedIn Account https://www.linkedin.com/in/amos-moyo-342976193/

GitHub Account https://github.com/amosmoyo

Profile

I am a graduate from Kenyatta University, I did a bachelors course in Mathematics and Computer Science. I am a softwaredeveloper mostly I specialize in web development and Data analysis. I love developing. I have been coding for about three years now. I use; JavaScript, Python, NodeJS, Mongo DB, MySQL, Angular, React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap and Angular Materials. Apart from coding, I do online writing and transcribing as a part time job.

Employment History

Full Stack Web Developer at Fleetsimplify (Instadriver)

November-to-December 2021

I was a full-stack web developer at Fleetsimplify for two months where I help in developing api's and performing integration with Frontend UI components using react-redux. We were basically developed two modules.

JavaScript Mentor at Andela Kenya

April 2019-December 2019

I was a Mentor (**JavaScript Mentor**) in the Google **Africa Developers Scholarship ALC-4.** I used to mentor novices during their projects and assignments. I was also a meet ups organizer. I used to review others developer's codes and helpedin debug and updating code. I helped also in documenting group projects.

Cloth Draper at Gikomba Kenya

November 2019 to present

As a part time stuff I help my uncle to sell second hand clothes at Gikomba.

Education

Bachelor of Science (Mathematics and Computer Science at Kenyatta University, Nairobi

August 2017-April 2021

Working with computers was always my dream. Taking a course in Mathematics and Computer Science has been a great thing for me, I have been able to discover the power behind computers and have had the chance work with great tools and technologies

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education.

February 2013-December 2016

I completed my Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education and got 73/84 is approximate to grade B+

Links and Portfolios

Linkedin Learning Platform	https://www.linkedin.com/learning/me?trk=nav_neptune_learning	
Linkedin Account	https://www.linkedin.com/in/amos-moyo-342976193/	
Photo Gallery Web Application	https://young-wave-52092.herokuapp.com/	
BuildForSDG Zero Hunger App	https://buildforsdg.github.io/team-132-frontend/	
Simple Shopping Web App	https://amosmoyo.github.io/HCIGROUP-AREPO4/	
COVID-ESTIMATOR	https://amosmoyo.github.io/COVID19-ESTIMATOR/	
SmartMeter Prototype	https://stark-everglades-36861.herokuapp.com/	
Part of (Instadriver team)	https://instadriver.co/	

Skills

1. Microsoft Office Word	Experienced	5. Angular 2+	Skillful
2. Microsoft Excel	Experienced	6. Non-Relational Database	Skillful
3. Git and GitHub	Skillful	7. JavaScript	Experienced
4. Non-Relational Database	Skillful	8. React	Skillful

Languages

English – Highly Proficient. Kiswahili – Native Language

Courses

Angular-2-and-nodejs-the-practical-guide	Udemy	December 2019 - January 2020
Excel with Microsoft Excel VBA User Forms	Udemy	February 2020 - March 2020
Learning Technology in the Information Age	Pluralsight	April 2019 – June 2020
Building a JavaScript Development Environment	PluralsightApril 2019 – December 2019	
How to Stay Abreast in the Ever-changing World of Tech	PluralsightJune 2019 – December 2019	

Extra-Curricular Activities

Peer counselor at Lodwar Boys National School

June 2015 – October 2016

Used to counsel peers on matters concerning drugs, early relationship and education in general.

Hobbies

Coding, writing, listening to music and reading.

References

Eric Araka, Networking Lecturer at Kenyatta University

arakaeric@gmail.com | +254727815187